

Daniela López Miño
UX- UI DESIGNER

NATIONALITY

Ecuadorian

CONTACT

Madrid, Spain daniela.lopez.mino@gmail.com (+34) 629 394 448

PROJECT PORTFOLIO

www.danylopezmino.me

LANGUAGE SKILLS NATIVE: Spanish OTHER LANGUAGES

English C1

DIGITAL SKILLS

Miro, Figjam, Figma, Adobe Suite, Visual Studio Code, Trello, Google Slides.

ABOUT ME

Visual designer with more than 12 years of experience. I have 5 years of specialized experience in UI/Ux design environments. My focus is on research, information architecture and creativity to create exceptional people-centered digital experiences.

WORK EXPERIENCE

05/05/2022 - ACTUAL - Remote UX - UI DESIGNER at Senirop S.A

- Multiplatform Design Problem-Solving Solutiong
- Leadership in Research, Content Architecture and conceptualization of Digital Products.
- Creation of user journeys, user flows, and task flows.
- Wireframing, prototyping, and interaction design in hi-fi with Adobe Suite and Figma
- Multidisciplinary collaboration with development team
- Continuous optimization, Agile methodology

05/2016 - **08/2021** The Male Box - Quito, Ecuador **PRODUCT DESIGNER at The Male Box**

- Creation of user flows focused on conversion and improvement of online shopping experience.
- Creation of user experience strategy and design e-commerce user interface.
- Usability and Optimization Tests to evaluate effectiveness of interfaces
- Leadership in Design and Business Strategy
- Effective organization of time and resources to comply with design project deadlines
- Experience in creating and editing visual content integrated into interface design and brand communication.

03/2012 - 10/2013 Quito, Ecuador

MANAGEMENT OF WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS MEDAGLIA - PRESIDENCY OF THE REP. OF ECUADOR

- Detailed analysis of requirements of 25 institutions governmental.
- Close collaboration with development and design teams to implement custom solutions on websites standardized.
- Quality guarantee in design and functionality, ensuring coherence and satisfaction of institutional leaders.
- Effective advice to more than 30 web administrators to ensure autonomy and successful management in the use of cms of the institutional website

EDUCATION AND FORMATION

2022 - ACTUAL- UX CERTIFCATE GOOGLE
2019 - 2023 - UTPL - JOURNALISM - EC
2004 - 2008 - VISUAL DESIGN - EC
Metropolitan Institute of Design

